#### SUKHADA DASH

FLATNO:302, Kalinga Residency Tangisahi, Tamando, Bhubaneswar, Khurda, Odisha.

Mobile number: 9840968392/8456824464 E Mail ID: sukhada.dash@gmail.com

#### **Professional Summary**

Having 18 years of experience as an educational professional I believe, Education administration is a fast-changing field that requires knowledge of modern classroom practices and insights in student behavior.

As an Educational Professional accomplished in Developing and Organizing teacher curriculum standards, assisting with lessons and collaborating with other professionals to provide the highest level of education for each student.

Eager to learn something new every minute. I love motivating my team to attain their incomparable and outstanding potential.

International Life Skills Trainer Certification from **Singapore** 

**Goal** – To be a leader in academic filled with vision of growing together and serving the nation with greater zeal and responsibilities.

### **Highlights**

- > Students are the main business to nurture and culture them in right sprit is my top most priority job.
- ➤ I have developed myself as result oriented professional in the area of academics as academic Councilor.
- > I have gained teaching skills and trained the trainer approach in developing my teaching team.
- > My approach throughout my career was to maintain high degree of academic excellence.
- > I work with collaborative and teamwork approach.
- > One of my strength is strong interpersonal and intra personnel skill while handling organizational need.
- > I keep my team motivated round the year by taking various initiatives for their development.
- ▶ Helping and guiding students for any problems that they come across academically.

#### **Core Competencies**

- > Creative Lesson Planning
- > Curriculum Development
- > Staff Supervision
- > Conference Presentation
- Creative Instruction Style and Techniques
- > Proficient in Creating and Maintaining Schedule.
- > Hiring and Recruitment Knowledge
- > Leadership Experience

- Creative Advertising
- > Strategic Planning
- > Classroom Management & Discipline
- > Standardized Testing / Scoring
- > Learner Assessment
- > Experiential Learning
- > Special Needs Students
- > Motivational Techniques

### EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

Sl No.	School/Institution Name	Roles	Location	Duration
1	TJS Public School	Founder Principal	Chennai	June 2018 – TILL DATE
			(Tamil Nadu)	
2	Narayana e-	Vice Principal	Chennai	<b>Dec 2016 – June 2018</b>
	<b>Techno</b> School	_	(Tamil Nadu)	
3	Narayana	Vice Principal	Bhubaneshwar	Feb 2015 – Nov 2016
	<b>Olympiad</b> School	_	(Odisha)	
4	Doon International	Teacher Coordinator	Bhubaneshwar	April 2013 – Jan 2015
	School	(PRT)	(Odisha)	_
5	One Ness International	<b>Academic Coordinator</b>	Bhubaneshwar	<b>April 2011 – March 2013</b>
	School		(Odisha)	_
6	St. Xavier International	Primary Teacher	Bhubaneshwar	June 2008 –March 2011
	School		(Odisha)	
7	Sri Aurovindo Integral	Asst. Teacher	Bhanjanagar	April 2004 – Feb 2006
	Education Centre		(Odisha)	
8	Saraswati Sishu Mandir	Asst. Teacher	Nayagarh	June 2000 – Dec 2003
			(Odisha)	

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **TJS Public School**

Key Roles & Responsibilities' as a Principal.

- ➤ Worked Directly with CBSE Board to obtain the compliance.
- > Encouraged and significantly increased parent involvement through collaboration with the School Site Council (SSC), Parent Teacher Interaction.
- > Implemented reading and writing workshop to increase the student literacy and support school reading programs.
- > Fostered meaningful relationship among students through student field-trip retreat and team work community service projects.
- > Identified success needs of the student population implemented and monitored academic and literacy programs toward those goals.
- > Designed and implemented student behavioral modification programs to reduce truancy, attitude and interactions with teachers and peer students.
- Established consistency among teaching population to deliver curriculum consistently.
- > Mentored teachers in the creation and implementation of powerful learning environments, lesson plans, and student assessments.
- > Developed and implemented a high quality professional development that was aligned with school goals.
- > Participated in various school reform efforts.
- > Coordinated the effective alignment of all budgets with curriculum and instruction.
- > Cultivated an environment that encouraged open communication with colleagues, student community.
- > Facilitated the vision of shared leadership while providing learner-centered leadership for all staff and students.
- > Modeled shared leadership and decision-making strategies and developed collaborative efforts between the school and community.
- > Developed and maintained an atmosphere of openness, confidentiality, and trust between and among

- all stakeholders: students, parents, and teachers.
- > Monitored standardized testing and prepared statistical reports showing teachers their students' strengths and weaknesses as reported.
- > Collected data using multiple qualitative and quantitative sources from secondary personnel and made leadership decisions based on data received and analyzed.
- > Set goals for curriculum, professional development, and secondary staffing.
- > Provided consistent feedback to all stakeholders on progress of building initiatives.

#### <u>Achievements</u>

- ➤ 2018 19 and 2019 20 TJS Public School got Interstate **BEST SCHOOL AWARD** for different kind of Co Scholastic activities.
- ➤ 2019 20 I introduced **INTERNATIONAL LIFE SKILL OLYMPIAD** and successfully scored 25<sup>th</sup> Rank International wise.
- ≥ 2019-20 I introduced **AMTI** and successfully scored State wise 6<sup>th</sup> Rank.
- ➤ During 2019 20 successfully achieved **ASSIST WORLD RECORD** in YOGA performance of my students.

### Narayana e-Techno Schools

Key Roles & Responsibilities' as Vice Principal.

- > Counseling Students and parents about our courses and programs.
- > Champion entire student cycle, Prospecting, Counseling, Admission, Orientation, Support, Satisfaction, Retention and Productive Output.
- > Interaction with students and parents on routine basis for doubt clearing, general counseling and progress feedback.
- > Conduct Parent Teacher Meetings, clarifying of doubts of students and parents as and when required.
- Monitor class schedules to ensure smooth running of classes.
- > Study material distribution and allocation.
- > Coordinate with other centers in the region.
- > Fee collection.
- Attending queries of students / parents related to admission, course fees structure, scholarship etc.
- > Having overall knowledge of all classroom and Correspondence programs offered by Narayana Schools in the State.

#### Narayana Schools

Key Roles & Responsibilities'

- > Being a class teacher responsible for maintaining class attendance register.
- > Evaluate student's academic progress.
- > Developed lesson plans as per the curriculum.
- > Conducting tests for students on a monthly and weekly basis to track their progress.
- > Responsible to conduct extra-curricular activities.
- > Maintain discipline in the classroom.
- > Prepare teaching materials for students.
- > Arrange Parents Teachers Meeting in regular base.
- ➤ Help managing student's behavior and developing different skills (emotions, cognitive, etc.,)

### **Doon International school**

Key Roles & Responsibilities' as Teachers' coordinator (PRT)

- > Interaction with students and parents on routine basis for doubt clearing, general counseling andprogress feedback.
- > Champion entire student cycle, Prospecting, Counseling, Admission, Orientation, Support, Satisfaction, Retention and Productive Output.
- > Attending queries of students / parents related to admission, course fees structure, scholarship etc.
- > Counseling Students and parents about our courses and programs.
- > Monitor class schedules to ensure smooth running of classes. Study material distribution and allocation.
- > Attending queries of students / parents related to admission, course fees structure, scholarship etc.

### Role & Responsibilities'

- > Teaching all areas of the primary curriculum.
- > Taking responsibility for the progress of a class of primary-age pupils.
- > Organizing the classroom and learning resources and creating displays to encourage a positive learning environment.
- > Planning, preparing and presenting lessons that cater for the needs of the whole ability range within their class.
- > Motivating pupils with enthusiastic, imaginative presentation.
- Maintaining discipline.
- > Providing feedback to parents and cares on a pupil's progress at parents' evenings and other meetings.
- > Coordinating activities and resources within a specific area of the curriculum and supporting colleagues in the delivery of this specialist area.
- > Working with others to plan and coordinate work.
- > Keeping up to date with changes and developments in the structure of the curriculum.
- > Organizing and taking part in school events, outings and activities which may take place at weekends or in the evening.

# **One - Ness International School.**

#### **Description:**

Oneness International School is behind to none in all but it has with the latest facilities on campus and a staff and faculty rich in talent and experience. Its expectations are high, not only from their students but from their staff as well. Each one must recognize the value of a caring and motivational atmosphere in partnership with parents for the future success of the students as they prepare for the opportunities, responsibilities and experiences of adult life. OIS, being an international, spiritual, outward looking, modern and ambitious school also reinforces from ancient cultures, structures, disciplines and traditions.

### Roles & Responsibilities'

- ➤ Handled daily classroom set up observing students' behavior and progress.
- > Developed weekly lesson plans in accordance with the school curriculum.
- > Collaborated with other subject teachers to monitor weaknesses and strengths of each student.
- > Communicated with parents to ensure proper guidance at home.
- > Assessed students in preparation for higher level of examinations.
- > Recorded and computed grades of students according to their academic performance.

### **Educational Snippets**

- > M.A. (Masters) in English.
- ➤ Bachelor of Arts from Godavarish Mahavidyalaya, Banpur, Utkal University in the year1999.
- > CHSE from R.S. MahaVidyalaya, Odagaon for the year1996.
- ➤ Board of Secondary Education Orissa from R.K Girls High School, Odagaon for the year1993.

### **CERTIFICATION**

- > B.Ed. completed From Gulbarga University, Karnataka.
- > NURSERY TEACHERS TRAINING (NTT) from Jay Bharat Nursery Teacher's Training Institute Bhubaneswar, ODISHA (RECOG. GOVT OFORISSA).
- > SANGEET VISHARAD (5<sup>th</sup> year) Master degree in music from Pracheen Kala Kendra, Chandigarh
- > International Life Skills Trainer Certification from Singapore.

## PARTICIPATION/TRAINING

- Nutan Acharya Prasikhyana, From Sikhya Bikas Samiti. BBSR.
- Nursery Teachers Training From Sikhya Bakes Samiti, Nayagarh.
- > PGDCA from NICE, Odagaon, (Sambalpur University).

➣

## SPECIAL ACHIEVEMENT

- Named Teacher of the Year for the Early Childhood Program.
- > Served on a committee responsible to assess revitalization needs and develop ideas for funding for Saraswati Shishu Mandir Odagaon.
- > Founder Member Saraswati Shishu Mandir, Odagaon.

# **PERSONAL DETAILS**

NAME : SUKHADA DASH

FATHER'S NAME : RAMNATH DASH (Retd. Principal Govt. Autonomous College)

**DATE OF BIRTH** : 22<sup>th</sup> OCT, 1979

**NATIONALITY** : INDIAN

**GENDER** : FEMALE

STATUS : MARRIED